you may be able to make a valid argument
for that bug by setting AC to high and
and then you know moving forward so I
see so what you're telling me is all of
my blind xsses that haven't popped are
attack complexity I know Joel that's
nothing the system being vulnerable is
not one of the conditions they just
haven't clicked it yet dude oh my God
Joel please
anything
[Music]
yo what's up everyone this is Rhino
Raider popping in to remind you to set
your CVSs Integrity To High by
subscribing to our YouTube channel at
critical thinking podcast drop us a
follow on Twitter at ctbb podcast and
like subscribe whatever it is you do on
your podcast app of choice so you never
miss an episode hope you guys enjoy the
show all right well I guess we'll start
off with news today then yeah yeah let's
do it all right
um let's see we got let's let's start
with the ntlm hash leaking thing so
MD SEC MD SEC Labs which I have not
actually heard of before uh released a
write-up for a cve that they found in
Outlook I almost said exchange but it's
it's outlook for once yeah
um and this is not particularly relevant
to book Bounty I don't feel but also it
it I think is is just a really good
example of an attack Vector for looking
at actual desktop applications and
looking at Microsoft Outlook so from the
perspective of your hacking on
Microsoft's program I think it could be
a really good
um a really good you know write-up to
read essentially what happened here was
they were reading and I love how if you
look at this right up like literally in
the docs it's like uh they're in the the
write-up they have like a screenshot
from the docs that says specifies the
file name of a sound that the client
should should play and this just goes
back to the preset that we've talked
about time and time again of like you
gotta read the freaking documentation
because sometimes there are bugs just
sitting in there waiting to be found you
could literally just control F4
yeah like I mean it's so fun it's like
literally written in the docs like it's
yeah yeah I remember I remember the
first live hacking that I went to
um there was 20 minutes left in the live
hacking event this was Washington DC and
schmiegel's a legend was like you know
what I'm gonna go read the documentation
with the last 20 minutes left he
literally went to the documentation for
the the target we were looking for
control F for URL found the first one
put it in there and it was an ssrf a
full read ssrm at the event and he
submitted it within the within the you
know last 20 minutes of the event so
crazy definitely bugs to be found there
um this one I don't I don't think is
particularly
um like I said applicable to the bug
Bounty world it's normally frowned upon
to send an email at all in the book
Bounty world so please do not do that
just to be clear everyone do not do that
this is an exercise of what it looked
like to find a cool bub on Outlook read
the documentation they used a DOT net
message kit Library
um to craft the correct file that they
would need to exploit this and then send
that message along and then when opened
by Outlook
um it it would trigger the UNC path
which is an attack Vector that we talked
about before because it came up in a
past life hacking event is like if you
have any way to make a desktop
application open a specified file path
on Windows and then you can leak the
ntlm V2 hash
um and I think that's I think I
personally think that that's quite
impactful
um it's certainly from a CVSs
perspective it affects confidentiality
um and also there's lots of other attack
characters if you're on the internal
Network
um because you can just relay that
authentication to a different
um to a different system and then you
know get access to further credentials
or gain access to that system so
definitely a cool attack factor to be
thinking of if you're looking at
um if you're looking at desktop
applications
yeah I mean it's a super super dope I
feel like it's one of those bugs that
you read through and you're like dang I
probably could have found that if I was
like yeah in like 10 minutes you know
like yeah but you know yeah the the key
factor being you have to be looking at
it you got to be looking man and that's
that's kind of what I'm telling everyone
with the with the uh with the World Cup
as well is like you sometimes you just
got to put in the time man um
tweeted about it earlier but I've got
some of the guys on my team that are
that are great and they're look out
there they're looking for the right
stuff they're doing the right things
there's no reason to justify you know
them not finding bugs uh besides the
fact that they're moving on too quickly
and not diving deep enough and getting
to those endpoints that are a little bit
harder to reach and so I I told them you
know let's let's dive let's take another
step deeper let's put at least 16 hours
into a specific part of an application
or a specific application before we move
along and if you don't have anything
interesting after 16 hours then maybe
it's just not the target for you so yeah
yeah
um we can talk about World World Cup in
a little bit let's um yeah let's finish
the news and then we can definitely I
think we brought it up all right what do
we got uh we've got let's jump down to
the Snapchat report yeah yeah sure I
mean yeah I feel like Snapchat a couple
years ago was definitely like really
popping off in the bug Bounty scene
because they had uh they had a couple
different Jenkins instances that were
open though or they were paying some
crazy bounties back in the day yeah
um but they are in the hacker one feed
again because there was somebody found a
really really really really simple eye
door where it's literally just a numeric
eye door and you you're able to uh
you're able to delete
um anybody's content off of their
spotlight
yeah no very very impactful
um I'm actually kind of I'm looking at
their their Bounty brief I'm kind of
surprised I don't hear about them more
often like I feel like no one's looking
at Snapchat and uh yeah they've only got
32k bounties paid in the last 90 days
and 15K of it was that one bug so I
think I think we might be sleeping on
Snapchat and and uh yeah so there could
be some good scope here for sure 4K
minimum on mediums yeah it's pretty wild
I mean so the one thing I will say is
that Snapchat security team is pretty
strong oh yeah
um they I'd say probably one of the
biggest reasons that you don't see a ton
of bugs on them is that their mobile app
is very very hardened
um so as a result you can do barely any
like hooking or proxying or any of that
kind of stuff without throwing off their
signature assigning algorithm that
happens on every single request that
goes out so oh do they do they do that
that's such a pain man yeah and it's
signed in a native library in the native
Library doesn't anti-hook checks and all
sorts of stuff so oh my gosh I mean
Spencer has a massive bot problem so
they did a lot of anti-botting features
like anti-botting features and stuff
that
now that makes sense and do you know if
they're using safety net
they work yeah yeah that's one of the
reasons why I know so much about
safetynet is because yeah back in the
day I used to write Snapchat bots so I
was I was I was really surprised when so
I hit Joel up the other day normally I
can nerd snipe Joel real easy and just
be like hey Joel this looks impossible
to to solve you know like wouldn't it be
crazy if somebody solved it and then
Joel will just like deep dive and come
up with a solution so I was like I think
let me go read the DM hold on let me see
if I can pull it out I think I said
something along the lines of like hey
Joel I think this is actually impossible
to to hook with Frida or something like
that and and your response is like yeah
yeah it's real hard yeah what yeah yeah
yeah I mean so all the safety net stuff
is like for those who don't know safety
net is essentially it's an attestation
uh Library tool that's built into
Android and it allows you to generate
these attestations that are signed at a
like a kernel like system level that
have a lot of different attributes about
like the device and it's
originally I believe it was meant for
like profile matching where basically
like you want a certain device profile
to be able to use your app meaning that
it has access to certain features and
it's not compromised in certain ways and
if it meets that criteria then you allow
them to log in by verifying the
attestation on the server side
problem is that that also gets used for
like anti-rooting anti-hooking all that
kind of stuff because it's it's a very
good library for detecting that kind of
stuff
and as a result if you verified on the
server side there's basically no bypass
because you can't bypass the server-side
check so
um Snapchat has been using annotations
for quite a while
um like I said I used to write Snapchat
Bots back in the day so that's how I'm
so familiar with all this kind of stuff
we uh we did spend some time and we
reverse engineered
um the safety net stuff down to like a
level where we could generate a lot of
it programmatically and then it's just a
cat and mouse game like at a certain
point they just keep updating it they
keep adding more checks and you have to
keep trying to reverse engineer them and
bypass those checks and you stick around
they could do it way faster than you can
so yeah it's uh it's definitely quite
difficult they also use this uh this
mobile security company who used to be I
don't know what they're called now I
think they rebranded but they used to be
called arcs in
um and they were using them for quite a
while to secure their native libraries
from looking and temperatures and all
that kind of stuff so I would guess that
is probably why their submissions are so
low it's just because the bear barrier
to hacking is like really really high to
actually like find vulnerabilities
without
triggering their anti-tamper stuff
but if you could get past that yeah you
could get some requests going through
your verb without triggering their
anti-tampering then you'd probably find
some cool bucks in this in this specific
report though it
it's just they go through their website
my my snapchat.com so maybe they're
they're expanding a little bit into the
web you know scope a little bit more and
there might be some vulnerable endpoints
out there because I'm seeing also
um story.snapchat.com so there it seems
like there's some decent functionality
in a web app not necessarily like one of
those programs where it's just a mobile
app so it definitely could be something
to look into yeah actually within the
last
I want to say within the last six to 12
months they announced Snapchat web which
is literally it's a web-based version of
Snapchat
um and you can do like a lot of the same
features that you can on the app but
through the web so my guess is that one
that attack surface is kind of ripe and
two they're probably not doing the same
level security stuff that they are on
the mobile app just because they can't
um so if you could figure that out again
you might find some really dope bugs
really cool stuff there and and one of
the things I wanted to talk to you about
this uh you know on the same topic was I
got an email I signed up for
um uh the bug Bounty explained uh stuff
from I'm gonna butcher this guy's name
yeah I'm not even going to try I'm sorry
dude
um but the guy that does uh bug Bounty
reports explained and he dropped an
email
um outlining
idors and like he went and analyzed 187
different reports
um and like sorted them into different
categories pulled statistics on Bounty
pulled statistics on what type of ID was
being used
um you know all that stuff and put it
into this like newsletter that he sent
out and I just I love stuff like this I
totally get off on stuff like this with
all this data and like analytics on on
vulnerabilities so
um that was the first newsletter of his
that I actually sat down and read and I
was really impressed with it
um so definitely I think he's pushing
out some really awesome content so go
check that out if you're interested in
in getting that delivered to your your
inbox every once in a while yeah it's
super cool to see that kind of data I
think like a really data-driven approach
to bug bunnies it's kind of a good idea
just yeah getting understanding for what
are other people finding how are they
finding it what are the common attack
scenarios because you'll find that many
many times bucks are basically the same
thing just copy paste it on a different
program yeah yeah for sure oh dude I
actually just clicked back to the
uh the idor and mandatory works for
Snapchat
oh I didn't know that okay is that where
he went from after Uber uh he went there
then he left he did a startup with some
of my buddies and then he left the
startup and he went back to Snapchat
gotcha gotcha nice I'm good glad to see
his face back in the community there
that's yeah did you notice that ape
Pfeiffer's there too who really yeah
really I haven't seen that guy in a
couple years they do have a built team
don't they yeah they have a pretty dope
team I I think I actually almost joined
there too geez yeah then you could get
on the inside and like see all the
places where your your your Bots were
getting foiled I know I know for real I
was serious
all right cool so let's see what else we
got on here um oh okay this is just
gonna be a quick little rant so let me
just talk about Jew Bob's tweet
um talked about you Bob a couple times
on the uh on the podcast before he
tweeted out the other day in most cases
described as user and enumeration you
can only ask uh yes or no questions
essentially about whether some email
addresses exist in the system in such
cases I would encourage you to favor the
term user existence Oracle which is more
precise totally agree with this take I
don't think a user existence or quality
of vulnerability I do think a user
enumeration vulnerability which is one
that allows you to either iteratively or
just all in one big chunk disclose all
of the users signed up for a service I
do think that is more of a vulnerability
um what do you think about that Joel
yeah I mean I think it's one of those
great bugs that you can use to chain
with another book so say you have
a password reset bug or a account
takeover but you need to know the user's
username or you need to know an account
that exists or you need to know an
account that doesn't exist that Spike
that I've had a couple times this would
be a great bug for proving that where
the team could easily say well how do
you know that an account exists how do
you know an account doesn't exist well
here's another book that I found that
shows it yeah absolutely and and I think
you can also use it in some cases
um you know to determine what what kind
of Direction you want to go with
um you know like for example if it leaks
a user ID or something like that that
can be really helpful uh for for you
know validating other attacks so
definitely cool thing I don't I don't
know man I feel like user existence
Oracle is a little bit wordy I might
just say user Oracle uh yeah but I like
I like the the concept so I wanted to
shout it out yeah yeah I think use
either Oracle is probably a little more
concise but
um but either way I think it's a good
distinction to to be making and it'll
help improve your bugs and and sort of
let you chain that stuff together even
now that you mentioned I was actually
thinking
um I have seen in the past where if you
get like an end point that you give like
an email or something and it errors out
and it'll be like you don't have access
to user ID and then they just put yeah
and the errors sometimes it pops up like
that good to keep an eye out for for
sure yeah those error messages are
always always very leaky yeah another
another tweet that popped up this week
that kind of caught my fancy was uh
anytime James Kettle tweets anything you
know I jump right on that I think he's
one of the few people that that like
actually tweets yeah I do I have I have
tweet notifications turned on for him
because he's not like you know there are
some people out there that push out some
really quality tweets but they also like
respond to every message you know and
and stuff like that so you can't you
can't you know put on tweet
notifications for them but for James uh
I definitely do and um and he posted uh
he tagged hacker one by bug crowd and
integrity and said hey why are we not
regulating why are we not standardizing
what it looks like to have a HTTP header
that that you know identifies as
specific ethical hacker to an
organization
um so they can easily search that in IP
logs I thought that was a great idea and
then Alex Chapman down below just kind
of says
um you know he he dropped a take on one
of the one of the programs out there
does uh you know where you check in and
I I think that's another way to deal
with the deal with the problem but I
really liked the the recommendation
further down in the comments that that
says this could also help with
verification if you like put a a um you
know a key out there or you sign the
header with something to prove that it's
you
um I think that could be really cool to
prevent you know black hats from putting
you know x dash ethical hacker colon
renovator in their header and uh and
impersonating me and then also so you
know dodging some logs when they're
actually doing some sketchy stuff
yeah I mean I would love to see more
standardization across the bug betting
programs in general or sorry the
Platforms in general yeah um I think
that there's a lot of room where they
could be
working together instead of competing
um and making things better for the
whole Community but I think a lot of it
gets sort of caught up in corporate
politics and yeah what not for sure
yeah that definitely does happen
which probably brings us to our next
topic AKA CVSs right let's talk about
like improving structural parts of the
Bugs Bunny reporting process like cdss
is probably one of the most flawed
systems that they have I see so many
programs that rely entirely on cbss as
like their their entire system for
paying out bounties and determining
severity and it's like
what
I don't know a single company that has a
threat model that's one-to-one with cbss
yeah yeah for
sure how the love hate relationship with
CVSs like
like anything else it's got problems and
thus we can hack it so there are some
scenarios where it's like all right this
attack is largely a let's say an
availability based attack right we're
dosing an account or something like that
but it also like leaks a little bit of
information right
um and so there's definitely ways you
know and that that would give a bump on
the on the CVSs score to it affecting
the confidentiality
um metric
and so I think there's also some other
ways you can creatively sort of chain
attacks together to try to gain higher
impact
um in the in the CVSs scoring system so
I think this is the companies like yeah
I'll just shout them out because
everyone knows already uh PayPal and and
Shopify they they stick very closely to
CVSs
um I think a lot of times you can work
that to your advantage so I don't I
don't mind it quite as much when they do
that but also the it's the it's the
times when the programs
downgrade it velocity of assess when
they feel like it and then stick to CVSs
when you can't get any higher that's
that's annoying yeah 100 maybe this is
one of those things that you have a
little more context and insight on as a
full-time hacker yeah what are like the
most like ripe areas that you can just
like increase availability for example
or something from sure none to yeah
that's a good question man let me think
on that
um
well one of the ones that comes to to
mind is the privilege required so one
you can a lot of times you can just uh
argue with the team about that and say
like hey if it's a self-signup account
it shouldn't be PR low
um there is evidence for that in uh the
standard if you read it I had a long
debate with a hacker one triager on
Twitter one time about this and I was
pretty happy with the results I think I
think I found some some evidence you
know in the in the standard that really
supports my position of self-signup
accounts being pr9 instead of PR low
um so that's one way but also if it is
actually PR low and and um you know the
the company has already established hey
this helps sign up accounts are PR low
we're not budging on that then sometimes
you can actually
um fudge it a little bit and try to get
your attack to be used so there are some
hybrid States sometimes in web
applications which I think are really
cool where like you're a guest but they
like issued you like this guest account
so you can check out or something like
that or like some ghost account
somewhere so that it can save your
preferences or something like that and
then in the flow later it converts it to
a full account one those are great spots
to attack anyway because anytime you
know they're signing up for an account
without actually having an account and
you're getting a different account type
then that's a great place to look but
also those ghost accounts you may be
able to weaponize those much easier you
might be able to just get hit an end
point and get a cookie and use those to
hit some of the other endpoints that
would result in your bug so that's
definitely one way to do it
nice yeah no I think that's um that's a
super interesting way to look at it I I
feel like I totally agree with you like
self sign up it's like listen it I don't
know why we're debating this anymore in
the industry I really don't I mean it's
like nothing is stopped like the same
amount of nothing that's stopping me
from doing an unauthenticated account is
what's stopping me from signing up and
then doing that request like it's
there's no barrier the barrier is just
one extra step that requires me to do
something for free with no verification
right like yeah and there are some
scenarios I think where companies will
say and this is this is another one of
the ones that you might be able to get
around but there are scenarios where a
company will say hey if you have to
verify your email
then that is PR low and so sometimes you
can get pr9 by signing up for an account
with not a verified email and accessing
the same functionality and then kind of
rolling with it that way so there's
definitely some ways to to eke it out
um one of the other things that I kind
of wanted to shout out since we're
talking about CVSs is the attack Vector
um metric which for most of my career as
a bug Bounty Hunter I've just kind of
been selecting Network and moving on
um but as I started looking a little bit
more at like Hardware devices and stuff
like that
um I noticed that there are these
adjacent Network local and then physical
um sort of
sections as well and they don't actually
decrease the impact of the vulnerability
super much so if you have you know a
company that that does CVSs for their
ratings and you know you have their
physical devices that you can look at
um you know you can make a strong
argument for a decently scored
vulnerability based off of you know
selecting these metrics realizing you
know telling the company to realize that
there are accommodations already made in
the standard for this
um and you know kind of selling it that
way
um because and that's something I I mean
like I said I've been doing for five six
years and I just found out about that in
the last like years so yeah yeah I think
that
um it reminds me there's a there's CBS
S3 extended I think it's called which is
like it's like extra layers on top of
CBS to try to make it more specific and
it's one of those things that like if
you were to do it for every single bug
you would probably go insane because
yeah it's so much effort and work and
being like is this which category does
this fall under and like all that kind
of stuff where it should be just like
look at what the impact of this bug is
is it a high or crit you know what I
mean
um
but
I don't know I just feel like it's
trying to make something fit like every
scenario that can't fit every scenario
you know what I mean just like leave it
as it is and yeah you know I feel bad I
I also
um I won't
um I tweeted about the program so if you
really want to be a sleuth then you can
go figure it out who it is but there's a
specific program that doesn't use a
platform that I hack on from time to
time and uh they do not use this they
use the owasp rating system and I it is
impossible to get a critical
vulnerability in that in that system
like it literally is like there's
there's just like you could be holding
you know you could be in their bank
account transferring money away and this
would be a medium like it's kind of nice
man so you know I I was a big hater on
CVSs
um for for a while and then I I went and
saw the Alternatives and I was like you
know what
CVS is saying so bad
oh this is super Wild
I'm just looking into this this is the
first time I haven't heard of it yeah
yeah no it's not super popular thank
goodness but um yeah I definitely like
CVSs more
um the other thing let's see what what
else what else are there ways to
escalate the CVSs the the other thing is
the attack complexity
um piece I think is is misunderstood a
lot and it's helped me make some
pretty good Arguments for
vulnerabilities that are sort of I
believe are dangerous but are also sort
of On The Fringe of whether they are you
know accepted in a bug Bounty program or
not
um and the whole concept behind uh
attack complexity is this metric
meant to impact the vulnerability score
based off of whether there is some
condition outside of the attacker's
control that needs to be in place and so
for example if you are missing you know
a piece of the equation or something
like that you may be able to make a
valid argument for that bug by setting
AC to high and and then you know moving
forward so I see what you're telling me
is all of my blind xsses that haven't
popped are attack complexity I know Joel
that's nothing
vulnerable is not one of the conditions
they just haven't clicked it yet dude oh
my God Joel please
um Let me Give an example for this so
that the community doesn't misunderstand
what I'm trying to say here uh okay okay
so actually this is a great so um you
may have seen on Twitter that the
um the uh rezo talking about uh uuid
idors
um props to rezzo for that thank you for
taking the flag and leading the troops
and making the case for uuidi doors
because I do think that there is
absolutely a large impact to those and
we've seen time and time again on
programs that use
um
uuids they've got like metric endpoints
that like dump all of the uuids and then
like once an attacker compromises that
if an attacker goes to that page once
and and sees that now they've got all
the IDS and they I mean those things
don't expire especially when it's you
know you know objects that are permanent
in the system so they can go back and
utilize those and yeah so anyway without
going on a whole rant if you're having
trouble with the team
um you know about uuidi door one way
that you could approach that is by
setting attack complexity to high your
severity will take a hit for that for
sure
um but I also think it's sort of fair
because the exploitation scenarios for
uuid idors are substantially less than
um you know innumerable idors a numeral
ID idors
um so that's another argument that I've
made
um utilizing CVSs in my favor as an
attacker which that that's kind of like
the thing that I wanted to talk about
with this with this session was like how
a lot of times when we submit a bug we
see it get downgraded and we get
disappointed what are the ways that we
can utilize CVSs to make a a good
argument for our bugs to be accepted in
a bug Bounty context so hopefully some
of the tips we drop
um you know we'll sort of help with that
one of the things I will say though and
Joel maybe you've got a better
perspective on this that I do is I still
don't fully understand scope
do you understand scope in CVSs yeah
um so I think it's meant to be like does
this breach across systems meaning like
do I get like
if originally I would have access to one
thing does my scope of access increase
as a result of this bug like do I get
access to
um like another user's bank account if I
could only
know they exist or something yeah like
like I don't know because it says and I
quote about changed in scope in this
case the vulnerable component and the
impacted component are different
and I've seen and I know you're supposed
to set scope to changed on xsses
um because it you know there's a browser
component that's that's the the impacted
component and then the vulnerable
component is the web application
um but outside of that like what if I've
got like
a bug that allows me to or blindx
success is a great example you know
blindex success would that I mean that
would be scope change for sure right
yeah for sure because like if it's
triggering on like an admin panel on the
back end or something like that then
that's totally different right
okay gotcha yeah I think that's the way
that I would view it
um yeah I don't know it's like one of
those weird things where it was probably
created for a specific reason like there
was I'm sure they had a specific
something in mind when they were like we
need to add scope into the CVSs score
yeah I'm just not really sure what it
was and why it was such a thing that
made it so it's in like the main factors
of a cbss I don't know
um yeah on the topic of uuids real quick
um so Uber used used uuids
um and that was something that came up a
lot in our bug Bounty program when I
worked there
where oftentimes people would submit an
idor and it would be like well it's a UI
ID uuids so do you have
like a user ID or something on the
receiving side of that message yeah so I
think like I definitely see both sides
of it I think from an engineering
perspective like it's very
easy to argue like
you can't enumerate idors or sorry you
can't enumerate uuids so you need some
other way however that being said like
we talked about
user existence Oracle or a uuid getting
leaked in an error message or email to
uuid like very simple idor that doesn't
give any info but it's their ID right
like any of those types of things you
could chain into a much more severe bug
by taking your idor that has a uuid and
now removing the uuid mitigating Factor
right and now you've just raised your
severity significantly yeah yeah for
sure and and that's a great reason to
keep you know these uuid enumeration
um sort of idors in your pocket and be
able to use them you know at different
times the most convincing argument that
I've heard though for engineering in
that scenario is is that what if I took
that uuid and I put it in an
authorization Bearer
or put it as your session token right
then then you know it would just be like
you're swapping cookies and that's not a
bug and I was like okay okay wait wait a
second though like that sort of makes
sense but it's not doing it for me like
and the reason for that and let me
explain the reason for that let me
explain the reason for that the reason
for that is that
these IDs are not treated like sensitive
material right they're treated like IDs
and they're put in URLs and they're put
you know in logs and stuff like that so
I I don't necessarily think that this
you know that that argument follows all
the way through because you know your
threat model isn't surrounded around
protecting IDs okay there it is it came
out that's what I've been meaning to say
this whole time your threat model isn't
built around protecting these IDs and
these being sent to pieces of
information so you shouldn't treat them
like they are does that make sense right
right yeah no 100 I like
severity should be basically impact
right yeah like that that's the way that
I view it and I think that's how most
programs should do it like cbss is a
semi-proxy to allow you to determine
like impact to some generic extent yeah
however it should really be like
what does it mean within your company
yeah like if you work at Uber what does
it mean for someone's uuid to be leaked
like can they access that full user's
object can they just log in as that user
like what does it mean within the
context of uber it doesn't matter like
is this a uuid like ruid's brute
forcible
okay so what it doesn't matter right
like are your uu IDs brute forceable
right like is there an oracle that makes
it so I can idor any account regardless
of the fact that you're using a uuid
right it doesn't matter if the
mitigating factor is there if it doesn't
actually do anything yeah no absolutely
yeah man I I don't know like I think
we've we've highlighted I hope we've
done a good job of representing the
highs and the lows of CVSs
um we're gonna have 15 different
programs that are emailing us this is a
very controversial topic I remember you
know I'm not one to really like get in
the Twitter Wars but like when I did get
in that Twitter war about CVSs I was
like in the weeds with it man like I I
don't know there's definitely you're in
the docs like pulling up the the
official definition it was I mean it was
like I was having a debate with my wife
or something you know
um but no um one other on the on the
topic of gripes with with CBS says I did
have one more thing that I wanted to say
though
um I'm a little frustrated by
the impact metrics so confidentiality
Integrity uh availability only having
two settings low and high
I think there should be maybe two
settings and then a modifier and and
here's why because so say you've got a
scenario where you let me pull an old
bug that doesn't exist anymore out of
the Hat say you've got an xssi okay you
include a script that script is
dynamically generated and it leaks to
you three pieces of information the
user's name email and phone number right
okay that is a user interaction required
bug so it's not something that
um you know affects users arbitrarily if
it was an idor that leaked the same
pieces of information I would make an
argument for confidentiality High
because it it affects every single user
in the system
it's confidentiality low because it's
just uh you know it requires user
interaction affects the one user not
mass exploitable now
let's say you had a different bug a bug
that was in idor that affected all users
and leaked credit card information
right that's a I think there should be
you know that's a super high that's a
super you know high impact confidential
confidentiality impact bug there
um and so I think there should be a
modifier on these to be whether this
component this um impact metric is
impacted at a scale across the
application
um or whether it's it's just localized
to the specific user
um and yeah I don't think user in action
required fully fully cuts that you know
does that well enough to to you know
warrant all scenarios
um so it would be great if there was
another modifier for those metrics I
think yeah I think it's one of those
things that like you could certainly
spin it to be like user and direction is
required but you could also spin it so
that it like what do you count as user
interaction and like where do you draw
that line yeah
yeah like it's super it's super fuzzy
where it's like high low none like I
don't I don't know yeah and I was hoping
to see some of these problems fixed with
CV SS uh version 3.1 but um you know is
that when they added the extended fields
or
um I'm looking right now I see so I
think it's called maybe we're talking
about different things but I'm seeing
environmental score is that thing you're
talking about I think that might be what
it is yeah yeah so actually maybe I
should sit down and and you know look at
all these different things that they've
added to the environmental score and and
stuff like that see if anything's
changed substantially because
um yeah I guess I have not super well
acquainted with CVSs 3.1 because hacker
one uses
CVSs three yeah it's the temporal and
the environmental metric groups those
are the additional ones I believe that
are like
report confidence confidential
confidentiality required availability
required base metric modif modifications
yeah man that would be a lot of forms to
to click I think even now I'm oftentimes
I just use the you know low severity
medium high severity critical severity
rating on hacker one and don't go
through the whole thing for the CVSs
just because it's really I mean it's a
lot of buttons to click for sure it's a
lot of buttons it's exhausting it's like
I shouldn't have to be the like it
should be pretty obvious you know what I
mean like this just feels like a crit
why because it's secret I don't know
what are you doing credit card
information yeah like this is a critical
I think anybody who worked as a company
would be able to be like that's bad you
know what I mean so I don't know I feel
very conflicted about it I see both
sides for sure
so those are the takes on on CVSs um
just to to summarize real quick
um you know we talked about using attack
complexity to your advantage
um we talked about trying to Pivot
privilege required low to privilege
acquired known through two techniques
one through talking to the team about
what PRL actually means and then also
through uh using guest accounts or ghost
accounts to Pivot
um you know privilege required into none
rather than low
um we talked about what scope means
which is new for me I I appreciated that
that little um explanation there Joel
um and yeah also we talked about the
attack Vector metric
um and you know using that to your
advantage when you're hitting
um the physical applications or the
physical devices so definitely keep all
those in mind when you're reading your
vulnerabilities
yeah that uh that's also something that
comes and bites you a lot with mobile
vulnerabilities with the like the the
access required is often like local or
physical yeah because like you need like
an app or something like that that's on
the device or like you have to pick up
somebody's phone in a coffee shop and
it's like they're really bad bugs and
they're not like outside of the realm of
like possibilities just that like when
you start to put it into the system that
isn't really designed for like all of
these bugs it yeah you get some kind of
weird results yeah and but like from a
mobile app perspective what is your your
threat model for a mobile app I mean
besides like them coming to a page
clicking a link and then it you know
using deep links kind of like we talked
about on the Deep Link episode
um there's not really a network Vector
because it's not like they have like
public IPS or anything like that they're
on a local network or they're on a
cellular network or you need to get your
hands on it or hit it via Bluetooth or
something yeah well there is that bug
that I talked about right so like the
Shopify bug that I found where yeah
intercept somebody's traffic on the
local network that's kind of an instance
but yeah a lot of the time it would be
like either no access or maybe like
physical access with like a bank if you
bypass their pin or something you know
what I mean yeah yeah for sure
all right I think that covers most of
the news topics in the CVSs
um you want to talk about some reports
sure yeah so this is a I tease you with
this a little bit yeah dude I want to
hear this I'm excited for this okay so
here's the story basically
um fisher Fisher and I Fisher amazing
hacker we were like we were having a
totally unrelated conversation
um I won't go into the details but
basically
um I like had lent him some cash he paid
me back by PayPal and when he sent me
the payment back he was like uh not a
payload or whatever like in his message
or whatever and he just put like you
know some curly braces and uh and I saw
it in my inbox and I was like oh that's
funny okay whatever and then uh you know
hour two later I let go I'm like sitting
on the toilet just like scrolling to my
phone looking through my notes looking
for through my notifications and I see a
notification on my phone says you
received you know X dollars from from
Fisher and underneath it it says not a
payload 66 instead of oh instead of oh
33 times too
oh hey oh [__] and so like literally in
the in the report the first image is me
messaging Fisher going dude holy [__] it
popped it worked
cheers
and I sent him two screenshots so we
pulled in um we were like really messing
with this because we weren't sure where
it was triggering we weren't sure if
this was on the phone or if it was yeah
was it a notification you said
yeah so it was a notification it was
like in the notification on my in like
your notification center so it would be
like you received a payment and then
underneath it with the message there
would be like
your template injection ah and so
um so we we were poking at it we were
trying to figure out where it was
and it turns out yeah it was a
server-side template injection ssti oh
nice and uh I actually found it today it
was apparently it was a cve uh not one
that we found but it was one from a
little bit earlier that I hadn't even
heard of so
um I guess they must have figured this
out after the fact because I don't think
we ever actually mentioned it in the
report that it was a cve but we were
able to get local file inclusion we were
really like read Etsy password off of
the um server and um yeah it was super
dope we got 26 grand for it no wait dude
you guys made so much more money than
that that transfer from the person to
person that's crazy yeah yeah no kidding
um and we actually we pulled in Andre
for uh for like the final final push
because he was helping us exploit the
the ssti yeah
um and yeah like I said after afterwards
I was just pulling up this bug and sure
enough they have it linked to a cve at
CBE 2020 12 668 and it's 12 68. yep and
it's in uh gin Java before 2.5.4
um it allowed you to inject uh into the
template and load arbitrary Java methods
passing in the context and that's how we
popped it I don't again I don't think we
actually knew that it was the CBE we
kind of just built our own payload out
of that out of pure exploration so yeah
um yeah super super dope bug it's one of
those instances where like definitely
was not looking for a vulnerability or
anything it just sort of showed itself
out of nowhere and one of those really
cool exploit scenarios yeah I totally
love that man you know like you whenever
you find an opportunity to hack on a
product that you actually use there's so
much more understanding of the threat
model of the attack vectors of oh my
gosh look at that you just said he just
sent me the payload that's crazy that's
so funny
um yeah no but there's so many there's
so many like you know different ways
that you know the the application better
than just a tester right so I'm a bit
and I told this to the people I'm
working with on the World Cup as well
like you know it
if you can go after of the targets that
we've got if you have any relation to
any of the pieces of the of the the
target you should go after that because
you understand that application so much
better you understand the use cases you
understand the The Fringe functionality
um as a user you have a totally
different perspective and that really
should be one of the one of the top
priorities of an application tester I
believe is to fully understand the user
and what kind of things that they're
going to be doing what kind of things
they're going to be prioritizing and try
to you know align yourself with that as
much as you possibly can that will that
will definitely lead to some cool bugs
like you guys found here so that's
that's sick man congrats yeah it was
actually paid as a crit too which is
which is super wild okay so okay okay
okay okay okay okay so we're going we're
going back to the CVS thing here for a
second
um why do people think lfis should or
lfds let me let me be clear lfds why do
people think lfd should be highs
yeah dude I think that's such a crit bug
I mean you basically have source code
access right it's like uh I don't know
like I think it's one of those cases
where maybe you get locked into CVSs or
yeah
right so they do lock it into CVSs but
but they gave it they gave you a crit
anyway but I guess SSDI you're actually
running code on the server so that's
that's different that's true I'll
actually tell you okay so here's here's
the cpss calculation attack Vector
network attack complexity low profile
let me let me get the calculator up okay
so Network okay uh attack complexity low
okay yep no privileges required low okay
so they give you low on that no none
that's interesting yep user interaction
none okay
scope change absolutely confidential
confidentiality high of course Integrity
High yep availability none availability
none okay so that puts you at a nine six
yep nice dude yeah no that that makes a
lot of sense I would say I think it
should be a 10 because I don't think
privilege required well actually let me
I take that
it's like what stops me from creating a
PayPal account you know what I mean yeah
but you have to put money on it so
you're gonna have to link a bank account
but we were testing with one cent it's
like oh were you really yeah yeah that's
true yeah but here's the other thing you
actually can you receive money on PayPal
if you've not added a payment method if
someone sends it to you yeah because it
just goes in your PayPal balance yeah
yeah so I mean that that should totally
be feasible to build a you know you know
pay someone in Bitcoin get it get sent
to your PayPal account and then you know
exploit it that way
um yeah yeah no I disagree with the pr
PRL on that and um the other metric is
that PayPal does
um you know
get 20 bucks to sign up or that was
their whole gimmick actually back in the
day when they first started was like if
you sign up we'll give you 10 bucks for
free which is brilliant marketing
gimmick by the way legendary
um but yeah free money if you sign up
yeah the Uber method not as much money
as you you're getting after that but
yeah that's true that's true yeah it's
funny because you mentioned um you were
you were saying like it should you
should really focus like as if you're
the user on like those high impact areas
yeah and like I think that's how as an
as like a hacker you should really view
severity right think about it from the
company perspective think about it from
the impact scenario again like if I'm
Uber what are the things I care about
the most user data private like trip
data uh location data location right all
these types of things so as an attacker
what should I be focusing on user data
location data sensitive data right yeah
yeah it's tempting too because a lot of
times I
well and it's also from the company's
perspective it's also a little bit
interesting because sometimes the
employees aren't as aligned with the
threat model isn't as aligned with the
businesses use cases either because
there have been some some times when
I've been like hey literally this bug
that I found invalidates your whole
business model like there is no business
model with this bug like you make no
money right
um but that you know it gets put it gets
put as a low or medium but that as a 5.3
yeah that says low to me
um and you know
so I think there's I know you had an
unfiltered access to our admin panel
yeah but but the CVSs but this is a
medium
user interaction really really required
um no okay
um
yeah so all right we're done with CVSs
CVSs we love you CVSs we hate you
um which one is it you'll never really
know yeah both yeah Joe you wanna
actually why don't you hit your second
report right away as well um we're going
to talk a little bit now about web cache
deception because we we told you guys on
the podcast that we would be doing that
um
uh in the future and so we've got three
reports today that we're going to talk
talk through I don't know my two are
kind of similar so I'm not sure I'll do
all the way through both of them but
um yeah why don't you drop that one uh
from a while back yeah sure so this was
um from a couple years ago I think it
was at maybe a live hacking event yeah
it was yeah I think it was a live Acumen
I was working with uh well we were
actually kind of all working together we
were the big disturbance team
um but Andre and I were the ones who
were primarily working on the specific
bug and we found uh we found an endpoint
that was basically doing caching
incorrectly so one of the API endpoints
on TechCrunch uh allowed you to
um hit it with like the specific
parameter that would change how it was
being cached
and so as a result we could actually
cache it for one user and it had this
sensitive token in there
um and then you could hit it from
somebody else's you know URL within the
same data center so we would hit one
endpoint get it to Cache this user's
token and then we would take that cached
URL with like a unique parameter
attached to it so that we'd know exactly
what it is and then we would load it
within an iframe we'd pull that token
out
and then we could use it to pull you
know pii we had um their full address I
think we had some credit card
information
um wow but yeah it was really cool it
was actually a High um and I think that
was probably because uh there were some
limiting factors where basically like I
talked about it need to be sort of
within the same like data center assess
location so for this event it was you
know we were geolocated in the same area
so we were testing from the same servers
so it popped easily for us but I think
if you were somewhere else you would
probably have to hop on a VPN but like
shouldn't have put that in the report
man you know everyone was going to be
SF area so that's true that's true this
this live hacking event man because like
like you said you know we were both
there you know seeing these reports come
in from Alex ACB
um and this was the event that opened my
eyes to web cache deception because
there were like three three really
really impactful bugs at this event from
Andre and you
um uh on webcast deception
um and then so I I left that event with
one takeaway of like I need to know how
to do this bug and it's super easy
um so definitely you know keep an eye an
eye out for that
um so let me just let me just refresh it
for the for the viewers here and you can
correct me if I got anything wrong sure
so you create a malicious page when the
user goes to that page you craft a URL
um and then you send that you make the
victims you force browse that in the
victim's browser
um what will then happen is the victim's
cookies will be used to generate that
Dynamic response and because of the way
that you encoded something in the URL
um in this case what was it did you put
anything oh you didn't even really have
to put anything in there did you you
didn't have to put like a lot of times
you'll have to put like dot jpeg or
something like that in the URL you
didn't even have to do that in this
scenario
um oh the cash prevention query
parameter that's that's that's what it
was yeah um yeah yeah and so you know
you set up this cash prevention uh query
parameter you get that value and then
when the page is dynamically you know
generated
it gets sent back to the to the victim
and it gets cached on the edge server
right so now that cache server if you
hit that exact URL from any you know uh
IP address in the San Francisco area or
whatever then it will load that user's
page response the response that was
shown to the user in their session with
their cookies to you without any cookies
or anything like that
yep is that right yep exactly solid and
then from there you would take that link
data and do something malicious with it
and yeah you know use it to like fetch
yeah exactly Pia
awesome dude yeah no standard web web
cache poisoning actually it's a little
bit this one's a little bit easier than
than normal because you don't even have
to do any tricky stuff yeah it's really
just like get them to cash this thing
and that's it
solid I I've got I've got one that kind
of takes it takes a little bit of a
different approach to it so this was a
government Target that I was working on
um
and uh somewhere in the application and
so I will I will note as well you guys
have to look when you're looking for
this you're looking for the a lot of
times what you'll be looking for is the
age header in the response which shows
how old this page is and something like
a cash hit or or you know a cash miss
anything but a cash Dynamic right
[Music]
um
and if you can see that and it's on an
asset that contains user and that page
contains user information then you've
got a webcast deception vulnerability
here
um so as I'm looking around in
applications one of the things I always
map out is
um where in the application this caching
is occurring because sometimes they'll
set specific paths like okay you know
slash assets is always going to Cache
anything that ends in JavaScript or
everything that ends in JS right so then
you know I might hit a URL that's like
assets
slash dot dot semicolon slash user or a
slash API user slash info right uh and
then you know dot Json or dot JS or
something like that and then that will
trick the front-end system or the front
end just to be clear the front end proxy
so the caching server into caching that
that asset and that's kind of what
happened here this was a technique that
I learned from Andre as well is that at
the end of and this actually happens a
lot in aspx sites I don't know why but
when you're dealing with an asps
application I see it quite often after
you put the endpoint you know whatever
dot aspx you put a percent uh or a URL
encoded
um question mark So percent three F and
then you put um you know a random string
and then the caching
extension so if you're gonna you know it
could be a JS could be a PNG could be
CSS it depends on their configuration
that's something you've got to find out
in the application then if you do see
that come back with a um
a cache miss or cash hit then um you
know you've got a vulnerability there
and you can just generate a random
string throw it in the URL force a
victim to go to that and then visit that
same URL from an unauthenticated
perspective as the attacker and pull
back that information so that's that's
what I had here the one reason I wanted
to highlight it is because of that
percent 3F piece putting that in the URL
tricking the URL into thinking that the
actual path ended in dot JS rather than
yeah
um you know dot aspx which what it was
originally yeah that's a really cool one
I mean like you mentioned caching is
often used for assets right it's for
like JavaScript images the types of
stuff that you don't want to be
reloading right it's like supposed to be
cached right and if they make a mistake
and they're caching
user data in some sense whether that be
a token or anything that's like specific
user specific that's not like a generic
asset like that's definitely a huge risk
for
um web cache deception and web cache
poisoning where yeah yeah and so the the
origin of all this the origin of the
problem with this is It's caching like
you're saying you know content types
essentially that it shouldn't be right
right so um you know most of the time
the reason why this configuration occurs
is because the caching server is making
a caching decision based off of the URL
rather than uh based off of the response
content type
right um and so that's that's definitely
you know if you can find a way to
validate that
um you know changing even if you can get
an HTML page to Cache anywhere you know
um that that's a that's a big that's a
big red flag and seeing if you can you
know try to trick the server into
caching the wrong HTML page yeah now the
one thing I will say because I feel like
semi-obligated to mention this yeah if
you're doing this sort of testing you
make sure that you're putting like a
random URL parameter or something on the
end because if you accidentally poison
you accidentally poison a production
website using just like a regular URL
that's used in production you're gonna
start leaking real people's data and
that's not good your program's not going
to be happy so if you see something
that's like using caching and you're
like I think I could probably poison
this put like question mark AAA or
something at the end right like make it
a unique URL so that if it does cache
you can still test it with your like
question mark AAA at the end but just
make sure that you're not using like the
standard URL because you're going to get
some angry program emails probably oh
yeah for sure and I think cash is one of
those things like DNS where it's like
okay is it DNS no it's cash then for
sure
um and so there's definitely ways to
mess that up a lot and it's definitely
possible
um I actually will shout out Loom which
is a company I use by the way I really
like Loom
um but they they had a caching problem
recently and it caused a whole security
incident right because I think people
were getting yeah we talked about this
last week I think yeah yeah so that's
that's uh that's you know another place
where you can see that in in place and
if you don't test responsibly you could
cause that problem for these giant
companies I've seen it happen time and
time again it is uh it's kind of a
really gnarly situation to put yourself
in so just you know be careful when
you're when you're doing your testing
and either don't test on prod or test
very safely on Broad you know yeah sure
um
have one other one I'm looking at it
right now I'm not even sure whether it's
worth
diving into to perfectly honest because
it's so simple well you know I'll just
I'll just walk through it real quick so
this is on an airline company
um this one's a little bit different
because instead of having the percent 3F
at the end like I did last time which
kind of tricked it into
um caching caching it because it
appeared to the edge server the caching
server that the
um uh the file type was JavaScript or
whatever in this scenario I actually
just added on to the end of the URL like
it was index.aspx Slash render reader
poc-random integer.png right nice and
and so then you know I would generate a
page that would have this random integer
and it would force the user to go to
that page the response would be cached
so there's lots of ways you can approach
this
um
just to you know take it away to
summarize it you know like you said if
there's like a caching parameter in
there that's a good indicator that there
may be some weird caching issues you
know in the URL
um the percent three F to trick it the
path they could be caching based off of
different directories in the in the
application and they also could just be
caching
um by just you know they don't care if
you have anything random at the end of
the URL in the path so you could just
add on slash slash whatever.png and get
a cache that way so those are some
methods to try out yeah 100 cool uh real
quick you want to talk about
um world cup and maybe the upcoming
event yeah for sure man uh yeah that's
right upcoming event I'll uh I'll skip
right to that one so we got Joel and I
both got invite for uh can we say I
think we can say location oh yeah it's
for La which I'm excited about because I
have never been to La
um so that's gonna be fun we are going
to be dealing with some Hardware
components which I think we can also say
um so that should be lots of fun really
looking forward to it I mean it's been
only a couple of months since we last
did some dope Hardware hacking bugs yeah
on this same Target actually so
um I think it's going to be cool
hopefully it's some new devices and some
new attack surface for us to poke at
um I imagine we'll be getting that stuff
pretty soon and uh yeah I'm excited to
see you in La I haven't been to an event
in person in a long time because yeah
scheduling and stuff and even this one
I'm I'm flying by the seat of my pants
the different flights and stuff but I'm
gonna make it work I'm so glad I'm so
glad you said you could make it you know
I you said it was going to be real close
and then yeah that's that's gonna be
awesome man yeah I got to be on the
other side of the country the day after
the event but I'm gonna take a red eye
make it happen oh my gosh are you
serious yeah yeah oh my God all right
we'll talk more about that off here I
got to get the details on that
um yeah World Cup how's it going for you
man
it's been it's been pretty good um so
I've been spending some time with a
couple of our team members I don't know
if we can say who's on the team but yeah
um and uh yeah we've been we've been
poking at some of the targets so for
those who don't know
um I think we could say who the targets
are right so yeah they're public yeah
stripe open C Yahoo epic games and
Shopify all very large big programs
great bounties and everything
um super challenging super hardened
targets but uh I know our team has
already found a bunch of really cool
stuff it's from you specifically
um and uh we've been we've been poking
hard to try and find some really really
dope bugs on some of those other targets
um but you know it's all about managing
time and and trying to spend your time
and hacking
energy efficiently you know what I mean
yeah for sure man I actually just got a
message during the podcast that they
fixed the bug already you know under 24
hours wow so that's if that tells you
how severe it is yeah yeah I'm excited
I'm excited for that one man it's the
only book I've got so far though so you
know nothing too crazy as a as of yet
but I think we'll I think we'll get
there and I know um some of the guys on
our team have some really solid leads
um got themselves access to some
let's just say some advantageous scope
um and so I think I think I think we'll
find some really good stuff there yeah
yeah it should be really cool so hoping
to see I hope they do some sort of like
recap or something afterwards yeah to
like talk about everything that happened
yep for sure we'll definitely keep uh
keep everybody in the loop about the
World Cup happenings um you know it's
it's been a really fun event so far to
work with some of the newer hackers as
well
um so for any of you that are looking to
get into the bug body space
um definitely feel free to apply next
year uh when they when they do the World
Cup it's definitely a great great
learning experience for everyone
involved yeah I know it's a little weird
for like the us because we're such a
massive massive country but I could
imagine for the smaller countries
getting connected with other people who
are like hackers within your region is
like pretty cool and and pretty awesome
to get to know people because like I
mean you could get connected with
another USA hacker like me and Reiner
there were like thousands of miles apart
so it's like you know it's not exactly
like oh I'll just drive an hour and you
know hang out we could do some hacking I
have not yet maybe yeah maybe get your
ass over to Virginia soon soon
all right man cool I think that the
lower the interest rates first yeah dude
for sure well this is a bug Bounty
podcast
triggered me Joel about to start talking
about this but we'll save that he can
nerd bait me nerd snipe me but I can
Finance sniper there you go nice nice
cool I think that's all I got is that a
wrap that's it for me all right peace
peace